Yulerik Sorensen

yulerik.sorensen@gmail.com I (503) 428-2923 I 4080 SW Ben Hogan Dr. Redmond, OR 97756

Professional Summary

United States Air Force Veteran going to school to acquire my bachelor's degree in Computer Science. I am an excellent learner that learns quickly and adapts well to a multitude of different situations. I can bring experience to the company in many different ways, with my willingness to excel and learn new skills.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
Oregon State University – Cascades, Bend, OR
Graduation: June 2022

Skills

Excellent leader Works well in fast paced Excels when challenged Learns quickly environments Manages time well Adapts well to changes

Employment

Project Manager – Talmage Construction – Redmond, Oregon – 05/2018 → 11/2018

- -Oversaw scheduling and building of 12 houses
- -Sought out and scheduled all trades for minimal time in between tradesmen
- -Kept site clean and safe for all workers
- -Ordered all materials from multitudes of different companies and arranged deliveries for proper trade at correct lot location
- -Answered or came up with solutions for problems that would rise everyday with different trades
- -Worked with variety of different trades every single day, from excavators to finish carpentry, from architects to real estate agents
- -Ensured subcontractors complied with safe work practices and OSHA regulations

Mechanic – PTA Plastics – Longmont, Colorado – 01/2017 → 08/2018

- -Conducted routine inspections and cleaning of CNC machines, plastic injection molding machines, routers, and multiple metal working machines
- -General mechanic for warehouse, building, and offices. Prioritized time to fix non-scheduled and scheduled machines
- -Kept up to date on planned inspections and preventative maintenance
- -Interpreted drawings and schematics to pinpoint sources of mechanical issues
- -Monitored shop equipment to maintain safe working condition

Aircraft Fuel Systems Craftsman – United States Air Force – Box Elder, SD – 11/2010 → 11/2016

- -Shift Supervisor, managed multiple airmen and tasks. Delegated tasks to airmen depending on urgency of jets
- -Red "X" waived and qualified. Grounding conditions of jet would not be lifted until final inspection and signature
- -Leader of multiple additional shop duties (eg. Training, bench stock, hazardous material waste, confined spaces and flight line safety and driving)
- -Three deployments and multiple temporary duty assignments, led to multiple medals, awards, and coins

Volunteer

- -Wrestling Coach, Ridgeview High School, 2018-2019
- -Habitat for Humanity Mar 2015
- -Feeding America September 2014

Accomplishments

- -Air Force Commendation Medal, Nov 2016
- -Maintenance Professional of the Year, Jan 2015
- -Air Force Achievement Medal, Dec 2014
- -Air Force Achievement Medal, Dec 2014
- -Air Force Achievement Medal, Aug 2014
- -Air Force Achievement Medal, May 2013